Finding Aid for the Collection of Research Materials Related to Linguistic-Psychological Studies of Genie (pseudonym), 1895-2003, 1970-2003 LSC.0800
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of research materials related to Linguistic-Psychological studies of Genie (pseudonym)
1895-2003
1970-2003
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rigler, David
LSC.0800
38.0 Linear Feet (76 boxes, 2 shoeboxes, and 7 oversize boxes)
"Genie" (b. 1957) is the pseudonym of a young girl raised in an abusive and isolated environment until the age of 13. The collection consists of material that chronicles her discovery and the study and rehabilitation efforts of researchers. Items include reports and essays; correspondence; notes; medical records; diagnostic material; legal paperwork such as depositions, summonses, and settlement agreements; pedagogical material; administrative paperwork; Genie's artwork; articles and clippings; photographs and slides; audio-visual videotapes, cassettes, and film; assorted printed material; and ephemera.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is closed to access, except for those individual files that are explicitly noted as open for research in the Container List. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Susan Curtiss, 2006.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 5404384
Biography
"Genie" is the pseudonym of a 13 year old girl who, on November 4, 1970, was admitted to Childrens Hospital Los Angeles as a victim of extreme isolation and deprivation by her immediate family. She was discovered after a Department of Social Services case worker took note of Genie when her mother, who was losing her eyesight, visited Social Services seeking assistance for the blind. Subsequent medical and psychological tests at Childrens Hospital noted that Genie had language and motor skills far below her age level.
In 1971, Childrens Hospital staff members intimately involved in Genie's case applied to the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) for grant funding to study Genie's case history and developmental progress during rehabilitation efforts. A grant was approved and from 1971 to 1975 Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles (CHLA) administered the study entitled "Developmental Consequence of Extreme Social Isolation," under the direction of Dr. David Rigler. During the course of the study, members of the research team included other CHLA staff, UCLA Department of Linguistics researchers (including Dr. Susan Curtiss and Dr. Victoria Fromkin), and a variety of external consultants.
In August 1971, it was determined that for Genie's benefit she should be removed from the hospital environment and be placed in a foster home. Because of her unique and severe case, placement was difficult and it was eventually determined that she would reside with David and Marilyn Rigler. The Riglers, in addition to being research team members, were Genie's foster parents from 1971 to 1975. This unusual situation would be a factor in a lawsuit later filed by Genie's mother.
In 1975, NIMH declined to renew the grant and the study came to a close. Genie's placement with the Riglers also came to an end. Now 18 years old and legally an adult, she was released to the care of her mother, who was unable to cope with Genie's special needs. Genie was then placed in a foster home, which proved to be especially detrimental to her progress and psychological well-being. As a result, she was readmitted to Childrens Hospital in 1977 for two weeks. Upon her release, Genie was placed in another foster home.
In 1979, Genie's mother filed a lawsuit (C 276 459) against Childrens Hospital Los Angeles and David Rigler, Howard Hansen, James Kent, Vrinda Knapp, and Susan Curtiss, individually. In the suit, she alleged that CHLA and the various defendants violated the physician-patient, psycho-therapist relationship of Genie and herself when confidential information was revealed publicly. The suit was settled in 1984 and the acrimony of the lawsuit temporarily severed the relationship between the researchers and Genie's mother, resulting in several years of non-communication with her and Genie. However, in 1992 Dr. David Rigler and Genie's mother reestablished communication, and the Riglers, subsequently, visited with Genie.
Although not indicated in the collection files, according to Russ Rymer, author of the book Genie: A Scientific Tragedy, by the early 1990s Genie was living in an adult home for the mentally retarded, where it is believed she remains in 2006.
Scope and Content
Collection documents the psycholinguistic study of Genie (pseudonym), a young girl discovered at the age of 13 to have been kept for many years in conditions of extreme isolation and deprivation by her family. The materials in this collection primarily document a National Institute of Mental Health study grant (MH 21191) entitled "Developmental Consequence of Extreme Social Isolation," which was administered by Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles under the primary direction of Dr. David Rigler. In addition to the formal study material, the collection also documents the foster care of Genie by David and Marilyn Rigler from 1971 to 1975, and a California lawsuit (case number C 276459) brought by Genie's mother against Childrens Hospital and individuals affiliated with the study. The collection consists of a variety of material including reports and papers authored by those associated with the study, study notes, correspondence, diagnostic and pedagogical material, medical records, Genie's art work, funding paperwork, guardianship material, legal material, photographs, and an abundance of audio-visual material.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Audio visual materials, 1970-1993 (44 boxes, 2 shoeboxes, and 2 oversize boxes), subseries A-E as follows:
1A. 1/2" video tapes
1B. VHS cassettes
1C. Mini DVCs and Hi8 P6-120HMP video
1D. Super 8 mm film
1E. Audio materials
Conferences, essays and reports, 1968-1983 (2.5 boxes)
Funding, 1970-1976 (2 boxes), subseries A-C as follows:
3A. Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles
3B. Grant Foundation
3C. National Institute of Mental Health
Guardianship, 1970-1978 (2 boxes), subseries A-D as follows:
4A. Correspondence
4B. Education
4C. Legal materials
4D. Miscellaneous
5. Lawsuit, 1978-1984 (1 box)
Miscellaneous, 1968-2003 (2.5 boxes), subseries A-D as follows:
6A. Clippings
6B. Correspondence
6C. Medical files
6D. Assorted notes and papers
Photographs, ca. 1895-1993 (2.5 boxes)
Research materials, ca. 1938-1994 (17.5 boxes, 5 oversize boxes), subseries A-H as follows:
8A. Administrative
8B. Correspondence
8C. Family history
8D. Genie's artwork
8E. Language, sleep and social behavior
8F. Miscellaneous
8G. Notes
8H. Testing.
Language acquisition -- Archives.; Social isolation -- Archives.; Child development -- Research -- Archives.; Feral children -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Abused children -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Psychologists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Childrens Hospital of Los Angeles; Genie; Rigler, David -- Archives
- 1. Audio visual materials, 1970-1993 (bulk 1970-1975); 44 boxes, 2 shoeboxes, and 2 oversize boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of audio and visual materials created during the linguistic-psychological studies of Genie. The material shows a variety of researchers, teachers, therapists and scholars interacting with Genie. The footage also documents Genie's behavior during her rehabilitation, life with the Riglers, testing phases, and everyday activities. Some of these materials, due to obsolete video formats and technologies, or the fragility of the media, may be inaccessible to researchers. Please consult the Manuscripts Librarian in advance so that viewing and/or reformatting arrangements can be made as appropriate.
  Arranged in subseries A-E as follows:
  1A. 1/2" video tapes
  1B. VHS cassettes
  1C. Mini DVCs and Hi8 P6-120HMP video
  D. Super 8 mm film
  1E. Audio materials.
  - 1A. 1/2" video tapes, 1970-1977; 37 boxes
    This subseries consists of video tapes taken of Genie between 1970 and 1977. The videos were numbered and listed in a basic subject index by researchers; this index is augmented by detailed descriptions of the following tapes: 2-3, 87-88, 90, 96, 101, 110, 111, 114, 115, 116. There are also brief descriptions for most of the tapes numbered 127-193. The original index and tape descriptions have been filed in box 1 at the beginning of the subseries. The main video format used was Sony Helical Scan (V-30D and V-30H) 1/2 inch video tape reels; unless otherwise noted, that is the format found throughout the subseries. For reformatted VHS cassette recordings of this material, see Subseries IB. VHS cassettes.
    - 1/2" video tape reel index and descriptions, ca. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Assorted typewritten materials documenting the original numbering scheme, description, and VHS cassette restoration for the 1/2" video tape reels. Descriptions for these materials were compiled for the finding aid by checking the original index against the descriptions adhering to, or written directly on, the tape containers.
    - Reel no. 1, 1970 November 30-December 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      No description given.
    - Reel no. 2, 1970 December 1-2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Genie at window; rehabilitation talk show. See index in box 1 for detailed description. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - Reel no. 3, 1970 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Genie interacts with others and Jean Butler. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 4, 1970 December 7-8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Banquet.
    - Reel no. 5, 1970 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Classroom activities.
    - Reel no. 6, 1970 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      O.T.
    - Reel no. 7, 1970 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Cutting with scissors; making snowman; visit with mother.
    - Reel no. 8, 1970 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Classroom with mother.
    - Reel no. 9, 1970 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Puppets.
    - Reel no. 10, 1970 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Prod. 1.
    - Reel no. 11, 1970 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Speech attempt.
    - Reel no. 12, 1970 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Outdoor play.
    - Reel no. 13, 1970 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Christmas.
    - Reel no. 14, 1970 December 26 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Reel no. 15, 1971 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Classroom. Poor tape for the first half.
    - Reel no. 16, 1971 January 12-13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Rigler, first testing with Leiter; with mother; dollhouse. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - Reel no. 17, 1971 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Mother's visit. Poor tape quality, except last third.
    - Reel no. 18, 1971 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Doll play; Genie and James Kent.
    - Reel no. 19, 1971 January 14 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Washing table; matching words.
    - Reel no. 20, 1971 January 14 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Doll house; optician.
    - Reel no. 21, 1971 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      With June Forer.
    - Reel no. 22, 1971 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Reel no. 23, 1971 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Meeting Liz; cobweb. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 24, 1971 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Leiter test with David Rigler. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38 and 39.
    - Reel no. 25, 1971 January 21 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Tantrum; Yogi Bear.
    - Reel no. 26, 1971 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Reactions to Yogi Bear and Huckleberry Hound.
    - Reel no. 27, 1971 January 27-29 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      First day with glasses; mother laughing.
    - Reel no. 28, 1971 January 29 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Dancing puppets.
    - Reel no. 29, 1971 February 1-2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Outdoors with Samuel Kirk; testing by Mrs. Kirk.
    - Reel no. 30, 1971 February 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Painting with Butler's finger; covering cigar box; classroom.
    - Reel no. 31, 1971 February 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Irene Wiley.
    - Reel no. 32, 1971 February 3-4 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 33, 1971 February 4 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Bear; Tribbey Miller.
    - Reel no. 34, 1971 February 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Outdoors; Jack Block and Jeanne H. Block. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 35, 1971 February 5 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Jack Block and Jeanne H. Block; second attempt at pointing (unsuccessful), Genie ends by pointing with chin; balloons and gifts. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 36, 1971 February 9-10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Turtles.
    - Reel no. 37, 1971 February 17-18 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Puzzles; waiting for mother at 10:00 am.
    - Reel no. 38, 1971 February 18 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Puzzles; pointing.
    - Reel no. 39, 1971 February 19 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Pointing; classroom. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 40, 1971 February 19 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 41, 1971 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Writing; typing.
    - Reel no. 42, 1971 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Reel no. 43, 1971 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Rehabilitation; record player.
    - Reel no. 44, 1971 March 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      In group drawing; listening to records.
    - Reel no. 45, 1971 March 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Parquetry blocks; puzzles. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 46, 1971 March 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Mother enters.
    - Reel no. 47, 1971 March 3-5 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Outdoors; Edward Klima.
    - Reel no. 48, 1971 March 8 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Classroom.
    - Reel no. 49, 1971 March 9 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Alphabet match up puzzle. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 50, 1971 March 10 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Greeting mother, etc.; last few minutes of tantrum. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 51, 1971 March 11 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      First craft session with Mrs. Smith; alphabet match up puzzle. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 52, 1971 March 12-15 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Classroom; wagon play. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 53, 1971 March 15 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Wagon; tantrum; Jay Shurley. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B). VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 54, 1971 March 17-18 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Mother; "come."
    - Reel no. 55, 1971 March 18-19 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      With mother after tantrum. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 56, 1971 March 19 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      With mother after lunch; looking at science book. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 57, 1971 March 19, 22 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Scissors; tissue paper; attempting to cut ball. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 58, 1971 March 23-24 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Swinging and standing in swing; getting ready to go outside. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 59, 1971 March 24 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      With mother indoors and discussion of birthday; outdoors in swing with mother; trying horse. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 60, 1971 March 26, 29 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      No description given. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 61, 1971 March 29-31 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Yogi Bear; at table; going out. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 62, 1971 March 29 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Yogi Bear. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 63, 1971 April 2, 6 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      With rabbit; back at rehabilitation. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 64, 1971 April 6 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      With rabbit at rehabilitation; gardening; waiting for Dr. Rigler and going outside. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B). VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 65, 1971 April 9 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Testing; Rigler. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 66, 1971 April 15, 16 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Beginning of birthday party. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 67, 1971 April 22-26 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Care of rabbit. Scotch brand tape (845-R125B).
    - Reel no. 68, 1971 April 30 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      On a stroll with Rigler; exploring apartment house, steps, and Laundromat.
    - Reel no. 69, 1971 May 5 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Waiting for mother in classroom; getting angry; mother's visit; Genie gets candy.
    - Reel no. 70, 1971 May 5 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Genie is ill; refuses chocolate and throws it away; mother's visit to rehabilitation room in CHLA; tantrum because not allowed outside. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - Reel no. 71, 1971 May 5,6 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      With mother after tantrum; Jay Shurley and Mrs. Wiley; "Similarity" lotto game; getting ready for film.
    - Reel no. 72, 1971 May 6,8,11 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      EEG testing; feeding baby rabbits, in classroom closet.
    - Reel no. 72.5, 1971 May 6,7 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      EEG testing.
    - Reel no. 73, 1971 May 12 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Mother and Howard Hansen; helium balloon and James Kent.
    - Reel no. 74, 1971 May 12,13 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Balloon with James Kent and mother; Yogi bear; Vickie, UCLA; watching herself on TV.
    - Reel no. 75, 1971 May 14 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      TV play rehearsal "Raquel Hicks M.D."; balloon; speech "come" and attempt "Dr. Kent;" waiting for James Kent.
    - Reel no. 76, 1971 May 17-18 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Drawing two balloons; waiting for James Kent; speech attempt "Dr. Kent."
    - Reel no. 77, 1971 May 19-20 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Showing two balloons on TV; watching TV; volunteer dress; cow puppet; "tail" identifying.
    - Reel no. 78, 1971 May 21, 24 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Ironing Mrs. Marilyn Rigler's dress; getting dressed to go out; tantrum in closet. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 40.
    - Reel no. 79, 1971 May 24 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Jean Butler's home. VHS cassette copy available for reference in boxes 39 and 40.
    - Reel no. 80, 1971 May 25, 27 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Reel no. 81, 1971 June 7-10 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Reel no. 82, 1971 June 12 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Classroom; drawing on board (house, James Kent, Genie); jumping; with mother.
    - Reel no. 83, 1971 June 16 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Reel no. 84, 1971 June 18, 24 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Cooking; in bed; garden hose.
    - Reel no. 85, 1971 June 24 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Reel no. 86, 1971 July 8-10 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Jean Butler's home. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 87, 1971 July 11-12 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Reel no. 88, 1971 July 13 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Jean Butler's home; eating, playing, in the kitchen. See index in box 1 for detailed description. VHS cassette copy available for reference in boxes 39 and 40.
    - Reel no. 89, 1971 July 13 or 15 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Jean Butler's home; interacting with objects and others. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 90, 1971 July 17-18 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Genie watching television; saying word "angry." See index for partial description.
    - Reel no. 91, 1971 July 19 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      No description given. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 40.
    - Reel no. 92, 1971 July 21 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Morning water play; eating lunch; this video follows a nearly sleepless night. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 40.
    - Reel no. 93, 1971 July 22 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Tree cutting. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 40.
    - Reel no. 94, 1971 July 28-29 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Toy, dog; washer and dryer installed; Roto Rooter. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 40.
    - Reel no. 95, 1971 August 4 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Kitten.
    - Reel no. 96, 1971 August 18 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Genie touches the Riglers' dog, Tory. VHS cassette copy available for reference in boxes 39 and 40. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 97, 1971 August 19 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Genie using play dough.
    - Reel no. 98, 1971 August 19, 21 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Visit of James Kent; Genie making bracelets and chains with pipe cleaners. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 41.
    - Reel no. 99, 1971 August 21 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Genie making bracelets and chains; Genie in pool and at dinner.
    - Reel no. 100, 1971 August 22 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Genie is frightened but enters kitchen and eats breakfast in presence of Tory.
    - Reel no. 101, 1971 August 25, 26 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Playing ball; interacting with the Riglers' dog, Tory; linguistic testing by Marilyn Rigler. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 102, 1971 August 30; September 12-13 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Block play; linguistic tests; alphabet letters. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 41.
    - Reel no. 103, 1971 September 14-16 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Exercises; alphabet.
    - Reel no. 104, 1971 September 25-26 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Exercises; opposites.
    - Reel no. 105, 1971 September 28; October 7, 12 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Exercises with Marcia; portions of tantrum during evening; recognizing the names of foods with Reba Braff and Marilyn Rigler. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 41.
    - Reel no. 106, 1971 October 12 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Recognizing names of foods with Reba Braff and Marilyn Rigler.
    - Reel no. 107, 1971 October 27 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      French test of Pictorial Intelligence; recognizing the names of foods.
    - Reel no. 108, 1971 November- December 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Marilyn Rigler teaching Genie to chew; language testing by Susan Curtiss.
    - Reel no. 109, 1971 December 3, 8 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Genie trying to repeat beats, exercises; tantrum outdoors, and post-tantrum moments.
    - Reel no. 110, 1971 December 9, 29 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Speech therapy with Reba Braff; language testing with Susan Curtiss. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 111, 1972 January 10 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      First session with Dave Rabb at JCC gymnasium. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 112, 1972 January 17, 18 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Prepare for sleep EEG test. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 41.
    - Reel no. 113, 1972 January 19 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Genie with Susan Curtiss and Marilyn Rigler doing the hokey-pokey; Genie makes a sandwich. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 41.
    - Reel no. 114, 1972 January 22 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Marilyn Rigler and Genie making play dough. See index in Box 1 for detailed description. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 41.
    - Reel no. 115, 1972 January 26 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Genie with Dave Rabb at JCC gymnasium; swinging from hands and jumping on trampoline. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 116, 1972 January 27, 30; February 25, 28 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Dental x-ray; bath (rinsing hair, drying, combing hair); CHLA, ear wax removed by Dr. Apthorp; JCC gymnasium, climbing. See index in box 1 for detailed description.
    - Reel no. 117, 1972 February 18 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Genie with Dave Rabb at JCC gymnasium; bat and ball, basketball, walking boards, trampoline, punching bag and balancing; CHLA Area C; physical examination. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - Reel no. 118, 1972 February 28, March 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)